<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hg8&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hg8&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/mango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mango/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    User Flag  Recon NoSQL Injection Blind NoSQL data extract Pivot mango -&amp;gt; admin   Root Flag  Recon jjs setuid exploitation       Mango just retired on HackTheBox, it was an Medium rated Linux box. As usual I really liked the whole exploration process especially the custom exploitation part and learned a bit about Mongodb. I know I say this every-time but this box is my favorite box so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traverxec - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/traverxec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/traverxec/</guid>
      <description>Traverxec was in my opinion a particular and interesting box. While being rated easy it still teach me a little trick and got me very frustrated at some point because it was super easy to overlook and overthink easy things. Still it was worth cogitate on it!
Tl;Dr: The user flag was accessible after using a Remote Code Execution exploit on the nhttpd web server running, giving us access to the www-data user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registry - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/registry/</guid>
      <description>Registry was my first hard box, this box was pretty interesting with real-life scenario like I love. This box shows the importance of understanding how things works &amp;ldquo;behind the scene&amp;rdquo; and to read all documentations carefully to not miss anything. I recommend this box for people who finished few medium difficulty boxes and wants to level-up.
Tl;Dr: The user flag consisted in finding an INSTALL archive containing install instruction and certificate to deploy an online docker registry, this certificate was used on the docker registry running on the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux install on Huawei MateBook Pro X 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/arch-linux-huawei-matebook-x-pro-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/arch-linux-huawei-matebook-x-pro-2019/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    Installation  Update BIOS if possible Create an Arch Boot USB Key Boot from USB Make Fonts Readable Connect to internet Partition and Format Setup Disk Encryption Basic Configuration Make the system bootable   Post Install Configuration  Connect to internet Create a regular user   Setup power saving  Get X11 Working Other useful app Setup my dot files Install a AUR Helper Automatic startx at user login Make Pacman faster   Various configurations  Setup the Linux Console font for HiDPi Setup user dirs Configure the Trackpad Hibernate on Low Battery Time Sync   Fixes  4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postman - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/postman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/postman/</guid>
      <description>Postman was an &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; rated box. It was quite quick but nice to solve. It can be really interesting if you want to learn and play with the now widely used Redis.
Tl;Dr: The user flag consisted in exploiting a redis instance accessible without authentication. From this instance you would bruteforce the passphrase of a SSH key found in a backup folder and use its password to pivot from redis user to Matt user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitlab - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/bitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bitlab/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    User flag.  Recon Web-shell as www-data Pivot www-data -&amp;gt; clave user   Root Flag  Recon Reverse engineering of RemoteConnection.exe       Bitlab box was an interesting box, user part was typical real-life scenario (actually meet this scenario during multiple pentests) while the root part was my first time Reverse Engineering.
Tl;Dr: The user part needed you access a Gitlab instance by using credentials leaked by one of the developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>whoami hg8 Information Security Researcher CTF Enthusiast &amp;amp; Bug Hunter  Hi there, my name is hg8, I am Information Security Researcher and CTF enthusiast. I set up this website to keep notes of my various work and especially CTF writeups.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing all of this down for mainly three purposes:
 Share it with you. Systematize it for future reference and improvement. Learn from your feedback.  Your questions and observations are very welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/craft/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    User Flag  Recon Remote code execution on API Pivot from docker container to user   Root Flag  Recon Exploiting Vault for SSH root password       Craft was very interesting and well designed box. It was a not so straight forward to solve and mainly based on configuration mistakes rather than exploits. That makes it more interesting in my opinion since we get closer to real life scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wall/</guid>
      <description>Wall was an interesting box, exploit oriented. The initial foothold was not straight forward to find and took a bit of time to finally figure out.
First thing first, let&amp;rsquo;s add the box IP to the hosts file:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ echo &amp;#34;10.10.10.157 wall.htb&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts and let&amp;rsquo;s start!
User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap scan:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ nmap -sV -sT -sC wall.htb Starting Nmap 7.80 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2019-10-28 16:25 CET Nmap scan report for wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networked - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/networked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/networked/</guid>
      <description>Networking was an interesting box. Focused on coding mistakes rather than exploit or misconfiguration.
First thing first, let&amp;rsquo;s add the box IP to the hosts file:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ echo &amp;#34;10.10.10.146 networked.htb&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts Let&amp;rsquo;s go !
User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap scan:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ nmap -sV -sT -sC networked.htb Starting Nmap 7.80 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2019-10-19 19:47 CEST Nmap scan report for networked.htb (10.10.10.146) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jarvis - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/jarvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jarvis/</guid>
      <description>Jarvis was a pretty straight forward box and &amp;ldquo;textbook case&amp;rdquo; style. While it&amp;rsquo;s rated as Medium difficulty I would advise beginners to start with this one.
It rely on bad configurations practices rather than already made exploits which makes it more interesting in my opinion.
First thing first, let&amp;rsquo;s add the box IP to the hosts file:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ echo &amp;#34;10.10.10.143 jarvis.htb&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts Let&amp;rsquo;s go !
User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap scan:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haystack - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/haystack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/haystack/</guid>
      <description>Haystack is a very interesting box to learn more about the ELK (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) stack which is becoming very popular. The user part is very CTF type while the root part is more realistic scenario.
First thing first, let&amp;rsquo;s add the box IP to the hosts file:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ echo &amp;#39;10.10.10.115 haystack.htb&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap scan:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ nmap -sV -sT -sC 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writeup - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/writeup/</guid>
      <description>Writeup was my first machine I solved to start my CTF journey. It&amp;rsquo;s an easy rated box but still interesting and perfect to jump into the CTF bath!
User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ nmap -sV -sT -sC writeup.htb Starting Nmap 7.70 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2019-09-01 10:39 CEST Nmap scan report for writeup.htb (10.10.10.138) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 7.4p1 Debian 10+deb9u6 (protocol 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>   Results:     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>