<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>john on hg8&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>/tags/john/</link>
    <description>Recent content in john on hg8&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/john/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAdmin - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/openadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/openadmin/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    User Flag  Recon Pivot www-data -&amp;gt; jimmy Pivot jimmy -&amp;gt; joanna   Root Flag  Recon Exploit nano SUID      OpenAdmin is an easy Linux based box, it need a bit of exploit, lot of recon, pivot and a bit GTFObins to finish, nice combo right? While this box is rated easy I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it for beginners since it require a lot a recon, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to miss important information and can be very frustrating if you are not used to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traverxec - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/traverxec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/traverxec/</guid>
      <description>Traverxec was in my opinion a particular and interesting box. While being rated easy it still teach me a little trick and got me very frustrated at some point because it was super easy to overlook and overthink easy things. Still it was worth cogitate on it!
Tl;Dr: The user flag was accessible after using a Remote Code Execution exploit on the nhttpd web server running, giving us access to the www-data user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postman - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/postman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/postman/</guid>
      <description>Postman was an &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; rated box. It was quite quick but nice to solve. It can be really interesting if you want to learn and play with the now widely used Redis.
Tl;Dr: The user flag consisted in exploiting a redis instance accessible without authentication. From this instance you would bruteforce the passphrase of a SSH key found in a backup folder and use its password to pivot from redis user to Matt user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>