<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sudo on hg8&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>/tags/sudo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sudo on hg8&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sudo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registry - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/registry/</guid>
      <description>Registry was my first hard box, this box was pretty interesting with real-life scenario like I love. This box shows the importance of understanding how things works &amp;ldquo;behind the scene&amp;rdquo; and to read all documentations carefully to not miss anything. I recommend this box for people who finished few medium difficulty boxes and wants to level-up.
Tl;Dr: The user flag consisted in finding an INSTALL archive containing install instruction and certificate to deploy an online docker registry, this certificate was used on the docker registry running on the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAdmin - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/openadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/openadmin/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents    User Flag  Recon Pivot www-data -&amp;gt; jimmy Pivot jimmy -&amp;gt; joanna   Root Flag  Recon Exploit nano SUID      OpenAdmin is an easy Linux based box, it need a bit of exploit, lot of recon, pivot and a bit GTFObins to finish, nice combo right? While this box is rated easy I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it for beginners since it require a lot a recon, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to miss important information and can be very frustrating if you are not used to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networked - HackTheBox</title>
      <link>/posts/networked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/networked/</guid>
      <description>Networking was an interesting box. Focused on coding mistakes rather than exploit or misconfiguration.
First thing first, let&amp;rsquo;s add the box IP to the hosts file:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ echo &amp;#34;10.10.10.146 networked.htb&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts Let&amp;rsquo;s go !
User Flag Recon Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the classic nmap scan:
[hg8@archbook ~]$ nmap -sV -sT -sC networked.htb Starting Nmap 7.80 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2019-10-19 19:47 CEST Nmap scan report for networked.htb (10.10.10.146) PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 22/tcp open ssh OpenSSH 7.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>